### Ali Rahimi



Esfahan/Iran +989135732644

alirahimii@protonmail.com

github | in linkedin

#### **SUMMARY**

I'm a Software Engineer. Assign me with some tasks, I'll find the solutions and get it done. With 4+ years of experience in develoement of Native Android Applications with the new stacks such as Kotlin, JetPackComponents (MVVM/ROOM/DATABINDING/etc), Dependency Injection(Dagger), Dataflow(Retrofit/Moshi/Coroutines) and etc.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Isfahan Univercity of Technology**

2013-2019

B.Sc. in Software Engineering

Course Work: Advanced Mathematics and Physics, Software Engineering Principals(Design, Architecture, OOP, etc) Data Structure, OS Architecture, Theory of Formal Languages(Compilers, Automata), Databases, Computer Networks, Software Engineering, IT Engineering, Statistics, AI, Computer Graphics, Economics, Microprocessors and etc.

#### EXPERIENCE

# **Full front-end Android Developer**

Sep 2014 - March 2015

PulseCo, Freelancer, IR

Pantomime Game/Application with cool UX and UI written in Java for android 2.1 to 4.0. The APK still works perfectly in android 10!

### iOS Developer

May 2015 - August 2015

PulseCo, Freelancer, IR

I learned native iOS development with Swift by developing an existing android application to iOS. I really liked and appreciated the Apple Architecture Design guidelines (MVC)

## **Full front-end Android Developer**

Nov 2015 - July 2016

TreeCo, Freelancer, IR

Android Online and Offline Game/Application written in Java. Key features: Notifications, Restfull and Web Sockets Communication With Server, Registration/Friend Management/Chat, Encrypted Coin System, Analytics and etc.

#### **Front-end Android Developer**

Oct 2016 - Dec 2016

Remote Freelancer, Malaysia

I implemented some basic data flow, authentication, subscribing to a payment plan and actual paying functionality with PayPall or Cards.

# **FullStack Developer**

March 2019 - August 2019

**Bachelor Project** 

Persian Sign Language Learning Assistant Android Application for children with the use of Visual Learning techniques by providing videos and images. New learning modules could be added to the existing app from a node js server.

## **Full front-end Android and Android TV Developer**

*August 2019 - October 2020* 

Remote Freelancer, EU

Complex Android and Android TV Application with a focus on the code quality and software architecture. Stack: Kotlin, MVVM, Databiding, Room DB, Work Manager, Retrofit, Dependency Injection (Dagger) and Kotlin Coroutines. Worked and communicated in English with a European company.

## SKILLS \_

Experienced: Kotlin | Java | SQL Familiar: Javascript | Swift | Python | C++ | Bash PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

User-Centric Approach to Design Apps | OOP | GIT | LINUX | Scrum | Architecture Design SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

ANDROID DEV Kotlin | MVVM | JetPackComponents | Dependency Injection | Clean Architecture

WEB/LEARNING React | Node | Apollo | Nextis

Native: Farsi Fluent: English Beginner: Japanese LANGUAGES